<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>An overview for AI in material</title>
    <link href="/2023/03/04/Overview/"/>
    <url>/2023/03/04/Overview/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“If, in some cataclysm, all of scientific knowledge were to be destroyed, and only one sentence passed on to the next generations of creatures, what statement would contain the most information in the fewest words? I believe it is the atomic hypothesis that all things are made of atoms.” - Richard Feynman</p><p>All the complex materials is made of atoms how the key ingredient for simulating these materials in computer is to get a way to describe these <strong>atoms</strong> and their <strong>interactions</strong>.</p><p>Think about it, all the hard-core course we learned from kindergarten to graduate school, the Newton’s rule, the electromagnetism and the quantum family buckets, they are all about clarifying the object and their interactions. Only for now and the level most people care about, the object is recognized as <strong>atoms</strong>.</p><p>Whether we wan to obtain an accurate description of chemical processes which chemists care most, the protein structure prediction which big pharm and biologist care most.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Why I start this blog</title>
    <link href="/2023/03/04/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2023/03/04/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Preface"><a href="#Preface" class="headerlink" title="Preface"></a>Preface</h2><p>We are now in the first year of the AI era. </p><p>ChatGPT has become an indispensable tool for work and research, and it’s the first AI application that has penetrated into our daily lives beyond just being a fancy game player or protein folding tool.</p><p>ChatGPT has made people, even those outside of the AI domain, realize that this is the future. It’s a significant step towards integrating AI into our daily lives.</p><p>Since the ChatGPT was launched, people around me, whether they are technical or business-oriented, or have no prior experience in coding, have been sharing tons of interesting ideas about how to use generative AI to build businesses or create things that can be drastically improved by AI. I normally get excited about their innovative ideas, only to find out that they actually know nothing about the basic coding of ML, let alone the transformer or the diffusion model.</p><p>Often, I realize that the various university courses or document materials that are available, though detailed, use outdated cases and are not of any practical use. Many times, I have to read hundreds of pages of documentation to use a computing package, or go through a 10-hour course to barely learn a language. In practical applications, many projects require switching between several different languages, and this learning method is not very suitable for most non-CS professionals.</p><p>Starting from a real-world problem, learning from classical code, and then fine-tuning it is a more efficient learning method.</p><p>As a PhD student in CS, I switched from fundamental physics study to artificial intelligence a year ago with zero background. I hope to organize a note-taking system suitable for myself, which can also record my growth and progress over the past year.</p><p>I plan to create two series in which I will share my learning notes in my research field, MLIP, as well as my interests, or areas that more people are interested in, and trade qualitatively with everyone.</p><h2 id="Outline"><a href="#Outline" class="headerlink" title="Outline"></a>Outline</h2><p>Here is a tentative outline, and I will attach links to each article after updating.</p><ul><li>Preface:</li></ul><ol><li>Applications of Machine Learning in computational materials</li></ol><ul><li>Fundamentals:</li></ul><ol><li>Download and Install: Colab</li><li>Formulating the problem</li><li>Theoretical basis (DFT)</li><li>Molecular Dynamics</li></ol><ul><li>Advanced topics: (continuously updated)</li></ul><ol><li>How to represent a molecule</li><li>Potential energy surface (MLP)</li><li>kNN</li><li>Gaussian Process regression</li><li>Deep Neural Network</li><li>Intuitive bias</li><li>Equivariance</li><li>Many-body interaction</li></ol>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
